35999 Weiss Rd Walker, Louisiana 70785 225.328.6236 | <u>lance.caraccioli@gmail.com</u> | <u>http://iam.mrburly.com/</u>

PROFESSIONAL OVERVIEW

Profile Headline:	Zend Certified Engineer PHP 5, Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, 3 Years professional experience with Zend Framework, 4 Years Professional Experience with PHP, CSS, XML, XHTML, Smarty, PEAR, wideImage, and jQuery. 6 years professional experience with HTML and Javascript. Have programmed professionally since 2005.
Career Objective:	I desire for my daily work to be honorable and purposefully focused on the growth of God's Kingdom. I will work in a position where team players and championship mentalities allow them to overcome adversity. I will become a lead software engineer. I will work for an organization that approves of open source development and contribution. I will work with a team that values the principals of agile development. I will work for an organization that values quality, continued education and pushing the envelope. I will work for an organization that believes innovation is a priority and is willing to invest in itself by allotting time for research and development. I will work for an organization that believes that technical debt should be kept to a minimum and therefore code refactoring is sometimes necessary on "working" code.

Summary of **Oualifications:**

I am a Zend Certified Engineer. I have advanced object oriented web application experience using PHP and MySQL on the server side and Javascript (iOuery), HTML, and CSS on the client side. I have experience building web services based on SOAP and JSON. Technologies I am most experienced with include Zend Framework, PropelORM, Doctrine ORM, PEAR, wideImage, and jQuery. I have used Adobe Photoshop and Gimp to routinely cut designer mock-ups and have experimental experience with other adobe related technologies such as Adobe Air, Adobe Flex, and ActionScript. I design software using software design patterns including Model-View-Controller, Decorator, Composite, Interface, Delegation, Factory, Strategy, and Front-Controller. Other work experiences include, accounting, charity work with LASBC, 7 years of professional baseball, and coaching. I also have nontangible advantages, related directly to my experience as a professional athlete. These include work ethic, focus, competitiveness, determination, maturity, composure, mental toughness, confidence, and a "how to win" awareness. I have a desire to learn and be the best at what I do.

WORK HISTORY

Worley Catastrophe Response (WCR)

January 2010 – Present Software Engineering; Software Design and Programming; Web Development My duties include **object oriented software design** including document intake methodologies, Entity-Relationship database modeling, work flow diagrams, specifications development, and implementation of software designs. I program using various technologies; PHP (Zend Framework, Propel, PEAR, wideImage, Smarty), MySQL, PostgreSQL, JavaScript (jQuery), CSS, wkhtmltopdf, and HTML daily. This job requires creativity and attention to detail.

Job Functions: Software Design; Database Management;

Programming/Software Development; Web Development *Industries:* Technology – Internet/E-commerce **Details**: At WCR I fill a number of various roles. I successfully implemented a Document Intake process allowing our field personnel the ability to scan large volumes of paper documentation into our system for processing from various remote locations. I refactored large parts of legacy systems to make them object oriented, easier to maintain, and easier to reuse. I lead our current push for more robust security by performing ethical hacking on our internal application. I enjoy building tools for others developers to use and have added many new tools to the underlying system architecture including reusable tools which allow for unified user notifications, PDF generation, document generation, and action delegation (generalized CRUD scaffolding). I have successfully engineered many subsystems dealing with various problem sets using well established software design patterns such as MVC, factory, strategy, decorator, flyweight, data mapper, and many more. Using Model Wrappers and Action Delegation I was able to successfully merge legacy systems with newer technologies allowing rapid development and a smooth migration path from legacy systems to those newer technologies.

Kfx2

April 2007 – January 2010 Software Engineering; Software Design and Programming; Web Development My duties include **object oriented software design** including Entity-Relationship database modeling, work flow diagrams, specifications development, and implementation of software designs. I program in PHP (Zend Framework, PEAR, wideImage, Smarty), MySQL, JavaScript (jQuery), CSS, and HTML daily. This job requires creativity and attention to detail.

Job Functions: Software Design; Database Management; Programming/Software Development; Web Development

Industries: Technology – Internet/E-commerce

Details: I started at Kfx2 while still attending school to complete my Bachelor's degree in Computer Science. Work at Kfx2 is intense. Developers are required to cut & code comps created by Kfx2 Designers and program the client and server side of each application. Larger projects follow large projects in a continuous procession of custom work. This environment has required the develop of multitasking skills in order to juggle many large projects at the same time, and the ability to identify common themes and patterns that can be reused across multiple projects. I have been the lead developer of most of the projects that I have worked on. A limited selection of applications which I have been lead developer on are listed below. Each of these were developed on an in house proprietary PHP framework, or Zend Framework.

- <u>Keeper Collection</u>
- The Shaw Center
- Lousiana Museums
- CSOBR
- Runnels
- LCMH
- Tiger Booster Clubs (Under Development)
- TAF Chapters (Under Development)

R. Brown & Company, Inc. November 2005 – April 2007 *Accounting / Bookkeeping*

My work at R. Brown and Company required attention to detail and self-motivation. My monthly work included bookkeeping, accounting, bank reconciliations, data conversion, data entry, spreadsheet design and programming (Visual Basic), W-2/1099 preparation, and general office work in a professional environment. These duties required strength in multitasking and organizational skills. I completed monthly work and financial statements for 15 or more companies depending on my coworkers work volumes.

Job Functions: Account Management/Planning; Bookkeeping

Job Functions: Account Management/Planning; Bookkeeping *Industries:* Accounting

Cincinnati Reds

July 2004 - October 2005 Professional Athlete I signed as a free agent with the Cincinnati Reds in 2004 and played for the Chattanooga Lookouts. Then again in 2005 I returned to Chattanooga. I started the season very successfully only to injure myself. My injury required surgery, which effectively ended my Professional baseball career.

Job Functions: Coaching; Skilled Labor

Industries: Arts & Entertainment - Other; Recreation/Parks/Sports

New York Mets March 2004 - June 2004 Professional Athlete	I was acquired by the Mets via the minor league portion of the "Rule 5 Draft" in December of 2003. I played for the Mets for the first half of the 2004 season. Job Functions: Coaching; Skilled Labor Industries: Arts & Entertainment - Other; Recreation/Parks/Sports
Cleveland Indians July 2002 - October 2003 Professional Athlete	In 2002 the Indians acquired my services when I was traded from the Dodgers organization. I played the rest of the season with success. I continued my success when I returned to Buffalo, NY in 2003. The off season after 2003 I became a free agent. Job Functions: Coaching; Skilled Labor Industries: Arts & Entertainment - Other; Recreation/Parks/Sports
Los Angeles Dodgers June 1998 - July 2002 Professional Athlete	I signed with the Dodgers in 1998 and was with them until 2002. During this time I progressed from Rookie level to AAA. I lived in many cities around the country. Listed below are my home team cities and the years I lived in those cities. Yakima, Washington 1998; San Bernardino, California 1999-2000; Vero Beach, Florida 2001; Jacksonville, Florida 2001-2002; Las Vegas, Nevada 2002 Job Functions: Coaching; Skilled Labor Industries: Arts & Entertainment - Other; Recreation/Parks/Sports
Louisiana All-Star Baseball Association December 1995 - August 2008 Coach / Accountant	I worked for Louisiana All-star Baseball Association (LASBC) in a dual capacity for many years. As a coach I have taught the game of baseball to other coaches, teams, and players that we have sponsored. LASBC is a non-profit organization that uses charitable bingo as a means of fund raising. Charitable bingo is regulated very strictly by the state. The state requires specific game accounting forms to be completed for each worker and for each session in which we operate. My duties involve accounting for specific workers and completing these forms. Job Functions: Account Management/Planning; Bookkeeping; Coaching; Community Service; Fund raising Industries: Accounting; Non-Profit - Associations; Recreation/Parks/Sports

EDUCATION

Southeastern Louisiana	Bachelor's Degree
University	Graduated: December 2008
	Major: Computer Science
	SELU GPA: 3.82; 4.00 in Computer Science Classes
	Cumulative GPA: 3.28
	Note: I also worked full time during this time period.

	Bachelor's Degree
Monroe	Attended: Fall 1995 – Fall 1998
	Transferred: 7 semesters completed
	Major: Computer Science
	GPA: 2.95
	Note: I also played for the baseball team during this time period

CERTIFICATIONS

PHP 5	Authenticate my status as a Zend Certified Engineer online by visiting the following link. http://zend.com/zce.php?c=ZEND012264&r=232542699

SKILLS

CSS:	Expert
HTML:	Expert
PHP:	Zend Certified Engineer
OO Design Patterns:	Advanced
Two Step View:	Advanced
Javascript (jQuery):	Advanced
Smarty Template Engine:	Advanced
PEAR:	Advanced
SQL:	Advanced
Database Design:	Advanced
MySQL:	Advanced
Zend Framework:	Advanced
Doctrine ORM:	Advanced
Ajax Methodologies:	Advanced
Git:	Intermediate
Subversion/Tortoise SVN client	Advanced
Adobe Flex:	Experimental
Netbeans:	Experimental
Java:	Intermediate (1 yr)
VBA:	Intermediate (2 yrs)

REFERENCES

Available upon request.